In this module I'll tell you about Chrome for developers, so we can navigate here and we see some
interesting documentation. First, how to be the first extension. We can see all of the tutorials,
how they are built, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, what are the extension, what they can do.
This is like a main component, so the manifest which is the most important, the extension
manifest is only required for the manifest big name manifest JSON. It also has to block
it in the root directory. We have content scripts, so it runs JavaScript in the context of web
page, service worker that runs in the background and handles some browser events. So for example,
if you want to check the website, how is it built, basically opening a new website, it will
run the event that will detect it. You have a toolbar action, so if I have here, I have four buttons
that will extract it, a site panel, it's possible to have a site panel on the right or again
from the pop-up, and we can even intercept block or modify a network request. This is mostly for
extension related to cybersecurity. All right, so this is how we can publish, in this case I would
tell how we can publish, so create a Chrome extension and publish in a Chrome web store to gain
an access to developer, Chrome dashboard. You have to apply for a license, and the license
cost five USD, which is not much. This is the initial fee, and then you have access to all of the
Chrome web store. These are the tutorials, so this is the first tutorial. You can create like a
manifest JSON, put an action. So we can, yeah, we can do it. For example, I have an empty file
Chrome extension, and what I'm going to do, I'll just copy manifest JSON, and then I'll just
open a new new file, and now I'll just make it like a JSON, and then I can open it in node, but for
example, and one is in node, but I can basically copy the all the links. So now I copied here,
this is name Hello extension, I will say "Curse", this is the name of it, this is the description,
if you have extensions, we have to clip this pattern, we have a description right here,
and this is the ID, especially the Chrome web store, and this is the inspect service worker.
So some of the extension doesn't have that. For example, this has because you obviously try to
detect how the website is built, and then return some information like extensive, it doesn't
hit because it just turns off to run on all of the extensions, and here we have a default icon,
have extension PNG, and there is a default pop-up HTML. So, and now we can run an icon to the
directory, you can even remove it, but we'll just create a HTML file, and now when I copy here,
I can operate this, and what I made to do, I can just copy this, and then go here and save.
So, we can remove that icon for a second, because we will not need it, and when it's already finished,
I can and try to add it. So first, you have to turn on developer mode, if you don't have it,
you just basically turn on, and then the options load and pack, pack extension or update will be
available here, if you slot and packed, then to go to extension that you would like to use like
current extension. Okay, and we, I removed the line, but I still forgot to remove obviously that.
Camera, and now, I will try retry, and as you can see, it's already here, curves,
and base level extension, and now we can pin it up, then when I pin it and press it,
we see hello extensions. So obviously now, if I make, because I have a mistake,
I change the curves, and I will just change my new extension,
and the version will be two that do, and I will change here,
hello word. If it's already done, I can save them both, and while I'm here, I just press refresh,
and you change, we see the version, we see the description, we see the ID, just like the version
here, and when I press it now, it says hello word. All right, this was our first script,
but we can actually add some pop up styles. So now I'll adjust it for our purpose,
before we dive into a cursor, for now, I'm just telling like the basics. So if I want to make
like another or toggle dark model, just to imagine how we can turn it on, so I can just
toggle, I will leave version as one, and we can even send maybe permissions. So the permissions,
usually, we can save permission, and for permissions, we will use scripting,
active tab. For now, it will be just for a test, and I can save it, and now we can create
some of the information, so we will need a JavaScript file. This way, we can obviously fire some
JavaScript, because we'll use the JavaScript inside the HTML. So we say we have a whole icon,
hello word. For now, we can actually remove it, because I don't want anybody,
I'll just use the script. In order to use the script, we use the button, and we can use ID,
and show the ID, and close it, double dark mode, and high button. And after that,
search up. So we'll just fire the script from Java, just launch JavaScript file, and first,
we have to close our JavaScript with this here, and that's pretty neat. So now we have to create
a file with that name and extension. So JavaScript file, I will go back to the folder,
I will open a new file, I will just open up to the script, and now I can open it here.
For now, I'm using just notepad, but you show the dive into cursor. So I created a simple file,
and for this type, we can actually try to get like how we can interact with JavaScript.
And let's go. I'll open now a Chrome extension. We say open folder, and we use the open folder,
Chrome extension, and load. After it's loaded, we see our files that I have created, and we can
even change it now from here. So now we can just ask agent, maybe I will just switch to agent,
I will use the composer one, and I can open a new agent and ask, for example, first. I want to
add our files in pop-up.js file, and then obviously, I will just ask pressing control comma,
I can switch between those models. So there is a plan, agent engine will continue doing some stuff,
plan it to just plan, and then we click the button to build the bullet point. But first,
I would like to ask. So they ask, we will not implement any code. First, it will review.
So now we see some implementations, and we can apply all, by pressing apply all,
it will just change some of it. And now, if I go to manifest JSON, we see the changes. So here,
it actually added a storage, change a lot of it, I just can keep it, and the pop-up is like
entirely code that was built. Okay, but I will remove it for now. And now we'll write just how we
can use it so far. So we specified in the manifest JSON, how HTML, that can't toggle and buddy.
So don't write it. I'll show you how we can use it. If you don't know, I will just get a document
which is the website, and basically it already detects just by pressing. And then,
I tried to look for a script and apparently that's true, and I pressed tap automatically,
it just fill up by first two or three letters. And now, I just save it. And then when I go back to
my Chrome, I will reload. And now, I'll just press it. Go here. We see you have a toggle dark mode.
It's pretty simple. I can create a daily code pop-up, show like random motivational code.
So I can go back. And we'll use now without using agent like previously, because I just
remove it, but as you can see, it just automatically populates. So I can open a manifest JSON file,
which is used like a free file from now. But obviously, this project is a little larger.
So I will change the name will be called. The description can be daily quarter,
like this code of the day, I pressed tap. And now, we don't need to actually need permission.
So I'll just remove it. Production will be pop-up edge to the amount that we will show it.
And now, and I will save it. I will go to, this is like a pop-up, hello, HTML. Okay. And here,
we have like some script mode. And now we just change it for now. I will use like a quote,
the P file. So I would say ID, quote, B, and script pop-up address, exactly. And then when I go to
pop-up, I will just try to put some like a quote. So I have to store it in some sort of the variable.
So this would be a cause, because we did not change. And this time, you have to specify
it's pretty ridiculous, but actually it's specified even some prompts on now I see it.
And then when I close it and use semicolon, but now I want to display it. So just get again,
document, get a lamb by the D, and get a lamb by the but I would just use maybe not text context.
Sometimes actually we have to know in our text quotes, my friend, so it's using like a random
quote. So if I like add something like a bug quote, and I will save it.
Now it's just written in the variable, it would just get like a cause. This is the pointer
reference to the calls link, because you just put a random so it has to know the number of
the variable elements here. And now if I refresh it again, go to the extension, press it's
called on the day, and when I press it, okay, we see it.